<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Machine Learning on this is a website for thinking</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Machine Learning on this is a website for thinking</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 10:32:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>old appearances</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/old-appearances/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 10:32:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/old-appearances/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have done a number of talks and appeared in a number of videos over the years. It has been some time since many of these videos and talks have been made (mostly over 5 years from this date), but there are some interesting nuggets amongst them. Most of these are on applications of machine learning in finance - you may find them interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;talks&#34;&gt;Talks&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;thrifting-alpha&#34;&gt;Thrifting Alpha&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thrifting alpha&lt;/strong&gt; is a talk about using ensemble learning to combine low alpha (weakly predictive) signals for algorithmic trading into stronger composite signals for trading a portfolio of stocks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>tezcat - AI retrieval in Obsidian</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/tezcat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2025 13:54:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/tezcat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Artificial intelligence (AI) products are now ubiquitous, but I think that few of them are able to hit on the right interface. Chat became the dominant functioning path too early, and now it is stapled onto everything, regardless of whether it is suitable for the medium of the information it is trying to channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to knowledge management, I personally do not like heavy usage of generative AI tools. For me the writing and the iterating is what makes the process worth doing, and from a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s44222-025-00323-4&#34;&gt;variety&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.paulgraham.com/writes.html&#34;&gt;of&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Understanding_Media&#34;&gt;works&lt;/a&gt;, we know that the act of writing contributes heavily to cementing new ideas in your mind.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
